alex karpinski

Building the Web

I am a software engineer with experience in web development, and system administration. I have been writing software and managing servers for over 5 years and have the hands-on experience to show for it. My background as a devops engineer for web applications has trained me to build and maintain server stacks that are reliable, efficient and secure.

Education

University of Rochester - Class of 2014 B.A. Political Science GPA: 3.6

Employment

UMass – Center for Educational Software Development May 2014 - August 2013

Amherst, MA

Software Consutant

I designed a plan for the modernization and improvement of Drupal development at CESD. This included the use of version control, development environments, issue tracking and release management. Improving the Center required research, observation, user education, and technical development.

GoSudo.com January 2013 - September 2013

Rochester, NY

Junior Operations Engineer

As a member of the Operations team at Sudo (gosudo.com) I was responsible for building systems that formed the company's technical foundation. This included writing configuration management, and designing the environments for testing, staging and production.

University of Rochester – IT Center Web Development March 2011 - May 2014

Rochester, NY

Web Developer & System Administrator

I built and maintained a Django-based web application for the University of Rochester's IT Center. My team used test-driven development and agile methods to build software that successfully raised efficiency and reduced mistakes at the IT Center. As the system administrator for the project I also designed and managed the server stack.

Freelance Web Design and Development May 2010 - Present

I have been contracted by Sleep No More NYC, UMass, and Lawrence University to build applications,

Skillset

Python Git HTML/CSS Nginx Chef Javascript Apache NodeJS Django Linux AWS **EmberJS** Vagrant Shell Script Database Design **REST**

12 Kettle Pond Rd Amherst, MA, 01002 234.738.0432

E-mail: me@alexkarpinski.com
Website: alexkarpinski.com